FWD Podcast bluntly free [music]
steps to discuss protection with
FWD insurance.  Just be blunt.
We are often told to be
sincere, right?  Every time a problem
hits us, we are
told to accept it, right?
What is sincerity actually?
Yes, sincerity means accepting the situation
gracefully.
So that means if we
have a problem or something, we accept
that problem.  Then ee we
adapt.  Indeed, maybe
at first we were sad and so on,
right?
Well, but after that we accepted it
with an open heart.  It means that this is what
I have to live in
my life.
Whatever the problem,
whatever the difficulties of life,
for example, right?  He
started from small problems, right?
For example, for example, waiting for a
friend to come, he said at 0:00, but
it turns out to be 07. He has
n't come yet and then it's 0:30, so
we feel uncomfortable.
We usually go home if our friends have
n't come for half an hour.
Yes,
usually I just go home.
Yes, but if we are at home,
for example, a friend wants to come to
our house, for example, at an appointment time.  wait
until, for example, 0.30 and he doesn't come
[laughs] that's the same, right?
Even though we were
ready to go together, we could wait
at home, for example.
Having freed up time like that,
having made time for that,
in the end we feel stressed, right?
Moreover, for ordinary people
who don't have strict time limits,
if they are even a little bit late,
they feel anxious.  Yes, there are people like
that.
But over time, after we
experience that anxiety, maybe we do
n't like that situation.  Then
after that we accept it.  That's what
sincerity is.
Hmm.
So accept the situation as it should be
with grace.
Accepting the inconvenience, huh?
Inconvenience of course.
Yes, maybe if the case is that the person falls late, it will
still be uncomfortable.  But
if the case is a person who has a
disease, for example, right?
Yes  so that you can't earn a living
anymore, for example, maybe sometimes,
especially if you're a man, you feel
useless, right?
Yes
What's the point of me being alive now?
Yes  What is the point of living if I am
struck down by a serious illness
that makes me unable to walk,
unable to go out, unable to work, and
so on.
Yes, it
could happen like that.
How can we be sincere if it's like that, when
every day we are given a constant reminder of
how useless we are.
Yes
Everyone actually has the potential
to be sincere.  I can he
live that person wants or not to try to go
in that direction.
So yes, people accept sincerely, that
doesn't mean that whatever the situation,
whatever the atmosphere,
they accept 100%.  No.
Of course, when people accept a
bad situation, they will initially feel
uncomfortable.
Hmm.  But inside each person
there is definitely a thought that we are trying to
adapt to that situation.
Well, in the end we can accept it
with an open heart.  That is what is called
sincerity.
Okay.  That means that sincerity is
actually a necessity in
this life so that we can live
more peacefully, right?
Yes  Yes  That's right.
But does sincerity kill ambition?
No.
Oh, yes you can.
No.  Because
I was like, "Oh, I failed, I only came in
third."  Yes, that means I think
this much is enough.
Yes
I don't need to think about being the first winner, there's
no need for that.
Sincerity is towards our situation at
that time.  But once a person is sincere,
then he will definitely try to
improve himself.
Oh I see.
Yes
So for example, for example,
what is your father's name now?
for example, this is an accident, right,
an accident, so yes, so
[laughs] a
broken leg, for example,
he,
because the doctor treated the broken leg with
surgery, but with the condition that we are not
allowed to walk for 1 month, for example,
h,
right, when we received it, 1
month, 1 month means I have to sit
at home, right,
ee, then I can't move,
even though I usually say that if I
exercise every morning, after exercising I go
out of the house, I meet
friends and so on, now
I'm not allowed to do this anymore.  Yes, right?  It will
definitely be painful at first,
but every human being has
the ability to adapt to
that situation.  So that after he
adjusts, he will accept
that reality with grace.
This means that he will be at home working,
perhaps using
internet media.  Then he might be able to
contact people with his cell phone, he
doesn't leave the house.  Yes, he has
accepted that fact.  That is what is
called sincerity.
Oh, accept the reality and then look for
another way, right?
Yes
The problem is that many people think that
sincerity is the biggest enemy of ambition.
Because if for example the person is someone who
I've accepted, I can't go out for
a month.  Whereas compared to people
who, for example, say, wow, I should be able to walk in
2 weeks.  Maybe people who have
ambition can walk faster
than people who are sincere.  I
accepted that I couldn't
walk for a month.
Yes, it's different.  If you are sincere, this will definitely
be accompanied by effort.
So sincerity is not without effort.
H,
as my father said earlier, when a sick person goes
to the doctor for treatment, the
doctor tells him not to move for 1
month, he has tried his best.
Hmm.  Yes, right?  After the effort,
he accepted this reality
and thought about how to overcome
the discomfort.  That's what is called
sincerity.  Not surrendering 100% means
not trying and then sitting at home
without doing anything, that is not
called sincerity.
What is that
?  That person is
resigned, right?  surrender in Heeh.  surrender
in a negative sense, yes.
H
means he doesn't respect
his humanity.  Because every
person always has the ability to
overcome their problems without
exception.
Hmm.
If someone feels that he
cannot solve a problem, it means
that he is at a dead end in his way of
thinking.
Yes, right?  I.
Well, if someone has experienced a
dead end, then he has to do
things that are out of the box
to make him feel relaxed.  Then he
can ee come up with ideas for ee
to adapt to the situation.
I want to
improve myself and so on.
So the first step before opening the
door to other ideas is to accept them first,
right?
Yes, it is definitely
clear to accept.  Oh yes, I'm in a situation
like this.  What should I do
next?
Yes  Without effort it is not sincere
.
H, because there are those who, for example, say, "Oh
yes, I accept that my situation is like
this, I am not successful, for example, in
my career."  Then after that, eh, it's
stopped, that's
not allowed.
Because for example, I am
also sincere that my parents,
it turns out, are not from a privileged family, that's what a
privileged family is now,
right?  Oh, no, that's not it, what's it called
?  I can't do much about it
.
Yes  If it's something that's just
gimmicks, it's not something
[laughs] that's
not the main thing, right?
Hey.
So, for example, if there are additional things like this,
sometimes what is it, ee,
impossible usually comes when
we have extraordinary ambitions,
even though they are delusional, but we pursue them and
don't let them go.
Sometimes it's impossible.
Yes  Being sincere is different from
having no ambition.  Different, very different.
Because ee ambition is part of
our endeavor.
Everyone has problems, they have to
try.   This
includes people, for example, asking
God, for example, to give them an
easy way to
deal with their problems.
He prayed that it must be accompanied by effort.
Hmm.  It's not just asking for it and
expecting it to fall from the sky, no.
Hmm.
Well, if such an effort
is considered as ambition, it is not
actually ambition.  That ambition is
beyond normal capabilities.
Yes  And usually people who are very
ambitious, for example, like Mike
Tyson, he said he
never wanted to take a fight if he
didn't feel he was the best in the world,
he said.
Which is something delusional,
right?   There's
no way he's the best in the world
.  There are definitely others that are
really great too.  But he said
so.  Basically, if he
wants to compete, he has to believe that he is the
best in the world, then he
can have a chance to win, he said
.  That's right,
that's just an effort to
encourage enthusiasm within him.
Yes
But does he feel that way when he is conscious
?  I don't think it's semayaan
.  It was just an effort to give him the
spirit to dare to face his
opponents, right?  But it's better to be
delusional, but positive, than like
oh yeah, I accept my situation
like this, I'm just like this.
Oh no.  The example that father gave earlier
also doesn't accept reality
completely, right?  There is an
effort.  Well, there are efforts
and thinking about how to solve the
difficulties that
he faces, you know.
So, what are you trying to do
?  The effort is like what my father said earlier,
for example
one is looking for opportunities,
namely finding ways to overcome the
difficulties faced.
Hehe.   Is
not it?  In order to minimize
the difficulties.
Hmm.
Maybe negate 100% maybe not.
But at least minimize it.
Hehe.
That's it.  What is the name of what you said earlier
?
Ambition.  If ambition is
excessive, it is called
ambitious.
Hmm.   Is
not it?  Well, being ambitious is not good
for your health.   Really
?
Yes, being ambitious is not good
for your health, but he has the ambition
to occupy
certain positions to get something
special.
That's natural.  Everyone must have one.
It's up to the person whether they want to do it or
not.
OK, the important thing is don't just give up like that
.
Yes,
yes.  endeavor ee try efforts from various
paths including this endeavor also not
endeavor praying like that
prayer is included in one of the endeavors
also
prayer is included in endeavor but physical endeavor
yes that is done
using our abilities,
our minds, and our physical
is ee the most important endeavor
then for example praying and
so on.  So, besides having to make the effort
mentioned above, we also have to
prepare for our families
.  If, for example, we suddenly
experience a disaster, such as illness
or something.  Is it important in my opinion to
prepare for the family?
Very important.  Why do I say it is
very important?  Because our family
is the first person to be affected
by our health problems.
That's number one.  Then number two is also a
person who is in a difficult situation,
for example, sick or whatever, the
most important thing for him is how
his family can adjust to
his situation
and be willing to accept
his situation with an open heart.
Hmm.  That's how it is
.  And it is not easy
because once someone is sick, it will have an
impact on everyone
in the family.
Hmm.
Starting from wife, children and so on
.
Hmm.  What are the
usual preparations?  Yes, financial.  Money, of course, I
think.
Yes, of course there is an additional fee.
People who are sick have
to pay additional costs.
Hehe.  Then there are also
shifts
in the role functions in the home.
Hmm.
There are also changes.  This means that the things that
the husband usually does
because the husband has health problems,
are forced to be done by his wife or his children
if he has adult children, for example
.
Hmm.  And this becomes an additional burden for
other people in the house,
so of course it will be
very difficult.
From this chat I learned one thing
.  It turns out that people who prepare are
not afraid but because they care.
Yes, it is true.  So, what does what
dad explained earlier mean?  We
need to try first then we can trust.
Correct.  Well, this is the matter of endeavor that
we most want to discuss further
, yes, in more depth.
Especially regarding readiness
to face health risks,
because they are the ones that are most frequent and
closest to our lives, right?  Well,
now we're here with Ms. Arti
, the head of transformation office at
FWD Insurance, who will help
us see how preparation can
go hand in hand with sincerity.  Good
afternoon, Miss.
Afternoon.  Hello, Mr. Risad.  Hello, dad.
once again, I finally met you on
this podcast.
Yes, I also have a lot of questions
in my head, right?
The first one is, in my
experience with FWD insurance,
why is it that health is often the
risk that has the most impact
on the family?
Hmm.  Okay.  So, I happened to
overhear my father's conversation with Mas
Risad earlier.  Well, so it's absolutely true what
my father
and Mas Risad said in the previous chat
, that when a
family member is sick, the
family is the first to be
affected.  Hey.
So, why does this actually happen?
Because when someone is sick,
usually many changes
occur in that family member,
within that family.  For example, like that
.  This doesn't only include
physical changes, but can also be emotional,
psychological, and even
affect the family's financial condition
.  Well, as
I said before, there are
psychological or
emotional impacts.  For example, we, we
may have experienced it too, Mas
Risat and Dad, for example, when a
family member is sick, for example,
we apologize to our parents or partner
or even our children.  There are so many
feelings that arise,
starting from panic, worry, right?
Even if the condition is quite severe,
the feelings that arise may be
feelings of helplessness and even
fear of loss.  Well, things like
that actually have the most impact
on the healthy, not the sick
.  Secondly, I totally agree with
what my father said earlier that when
a family member is sick, the
roles in the family can
change.
Hmm.
The worst is or what is the most
?  The impact is great when the one who is sick
is, I apologize, the backbone of
the family.   Is
not it?  This means that there must be a
healthy family member who can
replace this role.  That's right.
Working to earn income is not only
for medical treatment but also to
cover the living expenses of
the family.
Well, that's the second one, right?  Well, these two
things actually have a huge impact
.  Well physically, what is the most common thing
?  Tired,
weary, exhausted, yeah.  and even
if it accumulates for a long time,
ee, the health problems can become
ee, if the worst is a
psychological stress disorder, then you
have to go to a psychiatrist and so on.
Especially if you are treated in the hospital
, you have to go back and forth to the
hospital for check-ups and so on.
That's right.  That's right, Dad.  Well, apart from
that, there is actually a
fairly large impact, which is quite heavy and feels like an
impact on families, namely the impact
on ee from an economic perspective.
H
yes, as I said earlier,
if the backbone of the family
is sick, the impact will be
really felt by the family,
right?  Well, if we also look at it like that
, actually the cost of treatment,
the cost of medication or what we call
medical costs in Indonesia is not
cheap, it's not cheap everywhere
, it's
expensive.  The trend is
getting higher and higher
.  And there's some pretty good research
from Mercer March Benefit
which predicts that the increase in
medical costs could
reach 19%.
Wow, that's
how it is this year.
This year 19%.  Just imagine, that's
many times the inflation rate in
our own country, Dad and Mas
Risad.
So, yes, the impact was that when a
family member is sick, it
can definitely have an impact on the family's economic survival
.  It could be an
example to treat or pay for
medical expenses.  funds or
savings from the family are
used.
Yes
Yes, for example, emergency funds or
education funds, even those that
should be used for children's
education, can be used up for
medical expenses for sick family members
.
Hehe.  So, the child doesn't go to college
That's right.  I'm sorry, don't let that
happen.
So, that's why we come back to
Mas ee Risad's question earlier, is the impact
felt by the family?  Yes, in
my opinion, it really does feel like that.
According to FWD, it will be very much felt
by the family.
Hmm.  Yes, it would definitely be really felt,
especially if the head of the family was
sick, right?
Yes  Fish.
That's right.
Correct.  When my father was sick,
I immediately said, "Gosh,
what kind of work am I going to do later?"  [laughs]
Yeah.
So I'm sad, mixed with doubt, mixed with all
sorts of things, basically.  It's
really a headache.
Yes
Yes, right?  Don't let that happen, okay?
If it's not ready, the container will be a hassle, that's all
.  Even though you're already working, right?
Yes  But I was really
struggling at that time.
Yes  I think I can't even pay for my house's electricity bill, but it
seems like that.
[laughs]
That is.
Yes
I also experienced this when
I was sick and was treated in hospital every day
.
Hehe.
My youngest child is still in
college, still abroad, right?
Hey.
Well, he was stressed when he heard
that I was sick and being treated in the hospital,
he was stressed.
Yes.  What do you imagine?   The
continuity of his financing in
his school
might not be able to be completed later,
right?
That's right.  That's right.  Well, that's what
healthy people feel, sir, right?
Healthy people do.  That's why
many people say that when a
family member is sick, even
healthy people can get sick too.
Yes
Stress is definitely stressful if you're stressed.
That often happens.
Yes  Often.  That's right.
That's right.
Moreover, it is the same with mothers and children.  His child is
sick.
Yes
The pain is quite severe.  Requires
full attention.  Requires
large financing.
That mother thought about
the costs and thought that she would be
forced to go to the hospital,
going back and forth to the hospital.
Finally, his mother's illness was not felt.   Is that right
?  Because he kept thinking about his child, over time
he finally fell
ill.
That's right.
But there are many people who want to be ready,
actually there are many, right?
Everyone also wants to be
ready, right?
But what about the financing?
Do you at FWD Insurance see
this financing challenge?
Okay.  Well, this is a really good question
, Mas Risat.  So, to
answer that question,
in my opinion, access for
all people to
health insurance is very, very
important.  ee at least, at least
BPJS ee BPJS health is active and
can also be used when I'm sorry, the
illness happened like that, yeah
.  So, to complete the protection, it is
also a good idea to consider
additional or supporting insurance.  Well,
actually FWD insurance has
several health insurance options or choices
.  I
one of the good ones is
reliable free insurance, right?
This reliable free insurance
is actually a digital insurance
based on Sharia-compliant EE
and can be accessed
or obtained by customers either on
our website or on our digital platform
.
Oh I see
.  Well, the main benefit is also good,
yes, we ee finance or replace
ee inpatient care or inion.
Oh, it's
covered by this insurance,
like that.  And one of the other advantages
is that this insurance or this product can be
used cashless.
Oh,
cashless means that if, for example,
the customer, sorry, is sick and
hospitalized, they just need to show their
physical card or electronic FWD
insurance card and the costs
will be taken care of by FWD insurance.
Oh, so it's faster, isn't it?
That's right.  That's right.  No need to spend any
more money.  But this is of course in accordance with
the provisions in the policy.  Oh, okay okay okay
.
That's what it's called reliable freedom, right?
That's right, sir.
What does that mean?  It's
reliable free insurance.  So,
insurance can free customers
from these risks, help
customers to be free from
these health risks and can be relied upon.
Oh I see.  That's it.  If that's the case, then
if you're sick, just give me
the card.
That's right.
Problem solved.
That's right.  That's right.  But according to the
policy provisions of course.
that's for sure, right?
Yes  That's a particular hospital or
Well, that's right.  So the hospital that
can be cashless, eh, this father is a
partner hospital of FWD, right?
But there's no need to worry if
we go to a non-
partner hospital, we can replace it too.
Well, this is what we call reimbursement
or submission. Heeh.  replacement later
to FWD insurance.
The money was returned, right?  That's right.
So no need to worry.
Well, this other advantage is
perhaps one of our
quite good propositions in the market, that
goes back to my statement
that this reliable free insurance can
be a complementary or additional insurance
to BPJS health.  Oh,
so for example, if you were admitted to an
inpatient hospital and the costs were
covered using BPJS health insurance, that's all
.
The customer can apply
to us for the cost of the room.  Later,
50% of the room costs
will be replaced by FWD insurance.
Oh, so it's combined like that, huh?  combined
if e
the term is coordination of benefits.  Oh
okay.
That's right.   Try it
.
Cob.  That's right.  It seems like Dad is already familiar
with insurance, huh?
[laughs]
Yeah.
That's what it means, FWD insurance here
aims to improve or
upgrade
the class of PPJS participants or what?
So, actually, it's more like an
additional benefit for losses that
have
occurred to customers, right?  Sometimes,
right, Dad, when we are in the
hospital, or when we are hospitalized,
the costs incurred are not only the
cost of treatment, there
are costs for example for people
waiting, there are also
other costs, such as the cost of food for people
waiting and so on.
Well, that's what we can do, we
can't replace it, we can provide
daily benefit assistance.  So ee
what's it called?  More or less, it can
replace
the costs or losses that have occurred
to the customer.  Hey.
Moreover, he cannot work
so there are household needs
that cannot be met.  Yes, it is
true.  That's right.  So it is an
additional addition to replace the losses
experienced by customers.
Hmm.  Very good.
Yes  Can I ask one more question?
Please, Dad.
Last but not least [laughs] just kidding.
So, if
someone doesn't get sick at all for a year, is
there any benefit that can be provided?
Well, ee so if it's health insurance,
ee father, this sandal-free insurance,
ee the replacement is only
when the loss occurs.  So, it hurts
when the pain occurs.  Well, but
if for example the customer wants
the same thing, if
perhaps the customer is familiar with
savings or if there is a replacement
when the risk does not occur, we
have other products
.  So like for example
Heeh.  We have several other products
that usually have a return on premium.  Hmm.
So, the premiums that have been paid in or the
sharia contributions that have been
paid to us can be replaced by the
amount paid to the customer when the loss
does not occur.
But this is a different product from
free insurance.
Yes   The
product choices are indeed good.  The meaning is that the building is
really tall.  [laughs]
It turns out the product selection is really
extraordinary.
Yes  So, Dad has considered it, that
means [laughs] right.
Yes  FD.
Yes  Well, ee maybe back to the
previous topic, Mas Risad and Dad, okay?  So,
when we discussed
endeavor earlier, there is sincerity, right?
In fact,
we hope that this reliable free insurance and other health insurance
can be one form of
our endeavor.
Yes
So that you always stay alert, okay?  earlier.  So,
later, when we apologize for
the pain that occurs, we can
accept it because we have prepared for it
beforehand.
Honestly, it could be even faster.
Oh, right.  Of course.
Hehe.  Because the stress doesn't last too
long.
That's right.  The impact on the family and
also on oneself can also be
minimized.  That's right.  Okay, then
thank you very much to those of you who
have watched.  E see you in the
next episode of the E FWD Podcast
Ramadan edition with me and my dad.  Bye bye.
[music]